Register to The E.Y. Harburg Collection
Yale University Music Library
- Harburgiana, 1929-1968; Series II
  - Programs, News Clippings, Reviews
    - Finian's Rainbow (International productions) (Box 25, Folder 206)
      - London revival, [1959?] (Box 25, Folder 206)
        7" x 9" b & w photographs -- 30 pages
      - Gaiety Theatre, Dublin, Ireland, 1964 Jul 28 (Box 25, Folder 206)
      - Czechoslovakian production, 1965 Jun 26 (Box 25, Folder 206)
        Publicity -- 2 pages
        Programs -- 3 pages
        Photographs b & w 7" x 9 1/8"
    - Finian's Rainbow (Warner Bros. film, 1968) (Box 25, Folder 207)
      - Early film proposals (Box 25, Folder 207)
        Helen Winston & Meyer Levine to Sears & Roebuck, 1963 Feb 10 -- 2 pages
        J.L. Washburn, 1965 Apr 26 -- 2 pages
        N.R.B. Associates, Ltd., [1965?] -- 1 page
      - Warner Bros. production (Box 25, Folder 207)
        Publicity article, typed [by Burton Lane?] (3 pages) -- 2 pages
        Variety, 1967 Oct 5, advertisement, clipping & photocopy -- 2 pages
        The N.Y. Times, 1968 Mar 3, advertisement -- 1 page
        The N.Y. Times, 1968 May 26, advertisement -- 1 page
        The N.Y. Times, 1968 Sep 9, advertisement -- 1 page
        Los Angeles Times, [1967?], article, photocopy -- 2 pages
    - Finian's Rainbow (Promotional materials & scrapbook clippings) (Box 25, Folder 208)
      Scrapbook: pictures, statistics, reviews -- 3 pages
      Jacket copy for record album, holograph draft, in ink -- 8 pages
      Entry from Guide to Great Plays by Joseph C. Shipley, typed copy -- 1 page
      Tams-Witmark Music Library, Inc. advertising for show rental -- 3 pages
      Advertisement for record album -- 1 page
      References to Finian's Rainbow: articles, greeting cards -- 14 pages
    - Flahooley (New York opening publicity & news clippings) (Box 26, Folder 209)
      Reviews from national magazines, clippings -- 44 pages
      Reference to Flahooley: "The Critics," Theatre Arts, 1951 Sep
      Photographs, b & w, 8" x 10", original production -- 4 pages
    - Flahooley (New Haven, Philadelphia & California productions) (Box 26, Folder 210)
      New Haven playbill, 1951 Apr 9 -- 1 page
      New clipping: Hartford Times, 1951 Apr 10 -- 1 page
      Philadelphia playbill, 1951 Apr 23 -- 1 page
      News clippings of Philadelphia & New Haven reviews, photocopies -- 5 pages
    - Jollyanna (California production of Flahooley) (Box 26, Folder 210)
      Argument for revised California production of Flahooley, typed, carbon copy -- 6 pages
      Los Angeles Civic Light Opera playbill, 1952 Sep 8 -- 1 page
      News clippings of Los Angeles reviews -- 2 pages
      San Francisco Civic Light Opera playbill, 1952 Aug 11 -- 1 page
      News clipping, San Francisco review -- 1 page
    - Jamaica (Box 26, Folder 211)
      Souvenir album -- 1 page
      News clippings on Broadway production -- 3 pages
      Articles:
      The American Record Guide, 1957 Dec (pp. 185û186) -- 2 pages
      N.Y. Times, 1957 Dec 15, clipping, review of O.C. recording -- 1 page
      Hi-Fi magazine, 1958 Feb, re: Lena Horne -- 4 pages
      Karamu production, Cleveland, Ohio, 1960 Dec 16, Program -- 1 page, News clipping -- 1 page
      References to Jamaica: News clippings -- 2 pages
    - The Happiest Girl in the World (Box 26, Folder 212)
      Punch magazine, 1958 Jan 15, review of production of Aristophanes' Lysistrata [play on which Happiest Girl is based] -- 1 page
      Playbills: New Haven, 1961 Feb 18 -- 1 page, Philadelphia [no date] -- 1 page, New York, 1961 Apr 3 -- 1 page
      News clipping -- 1 page
      Article: The Diner's Club Magazine, 1961 Jul (cover photo & reference on p. 6) -- 1 page
      Photograph, b & w, 8" x 10", of production team: Lee Guber, E.Y. Harburg, Cyril Ritchard, Fred Saidy, Henry Myers -- 1 page
    - Gay Purree (Box 26, Folder 212)
      News clippings: reviews & articles -- 20 pages
    - Darling of the Day (Box 26, Folder 213)
      - Maried Alive (Toronto production) (Box 26, Folder 213)
        Playbill, 1967 Dec 4 -- 1 page
        Announcement -- 1 page
        News clippings: reviews -- 6 pages
      - Married Alive (Boston production) (Box 26, Folder 213)
        Panorama magazine, cover photo -- 1 page
      - N.Y. production (Box 26, Folder 213)
        Playbills, 1968 Jun 27 -- 2 pages
        Advertisement, reprinted from N.Y. Times -- 1 page
        News clippings: reviews -- 13 pages
  - General Writings about E.Y. Harburg & his Works
    - Articles, speeches in manuscript (Box 27, Folder 214)
      - "E.Y. Harburg" by Henry Myers, [1957-1958?] (Box 27, Folder 214)
        Typed draft, 2 carbon copies & photocopy -- 2 pages each
      - [E.Y. Harburg & Fred Saidy] by Lee Guber, [1960?] (Box 27, Folder 214)
        Typed draft, carbon copy -- 6 pages
      - "An Appreciation of the Lyrics of E.Y. Harburg" by Gerald Gardner, 1961 Jul 24 (Box 27, Folder 214)
        Typed draft & carbon copy with note to E.Y. Harburg attached -- 6 pages each
      - "Look to the Rainbow" by Barrows Dunham, 1965 Feb (Box 27, Folder 214)
        Typed, carbon copy -- 28 pages
      - Press release for N.E.T. by Geraldine Carro, 1965 Mar 10 (Box 27, Folder 214)
        Typed -- 2 pages
      - "Social Communication on the Musical Stage" by Barrows Dunham, 1967 Oct 2 (Box 27, Folder 214)
        Typed -- 10 pages
    - General references to E.Y. Harburg
      - News clippings & magazine articles, 1933-1968; 29 pages (Box 27, Folder 215)
      - News clippings, sources unidentified, [no date]; 13 pages (Box 27, Folder 216)
      - Scrapbook: "Harold Arlen-E.Y. Harburg Cavalcade" (7 pp.), 1 page (Box 27, Folder 216)
      - "The Perry Como Show" television script, 1959 Apr 25 (Box 27, Folder 217)
        Typed, photocopy (77 pp.)
  - Memorabilia
    - ASCAP Almanac, 1963 Apr (p. 4); 1 page (Box 27, Folder 218)
    - ASCAP Constitutional Amendment, 1 page (Box 27, Folder 218)
    - E.Y. Harburg song credits (Box 27, Folder 218)
      Typed, carbon copy [incomplete] (3 pp.) -- 1 page
    - E.Y. Harburg song & show credits (Box 27, Folder 218)
      Handwritten, in ink (2 pp.) -- 1 page
    - "The ASCAP Story," N.Y. Times, 1964 Feb 16 (p. 23); 1 page (Box 27, Folder 218)
    - Programs (Box 27, Folder 219)
      - Carnegie Hall Recital, Sinatra & Horne, 1963 Oct 5; 1 page (Box 27, Folder 219)
      - ASCAP 50th Anniversary, The Players Pipe Night, 1964 Mar 15 [flyer]; 1 page (Box 27, Folder 219)
      - Stars for Sane, Town Hall, N.Y., 1964 Apr 19; 1 page (Box 27, Folder 219)
      - Salute to American Musical Theatre, Manhattan School of Music, 1967 Apr 5; 1 page (Box 27, Folder 219)
      - "A Tribute to Dr. Spock," Stars for Sane, 1968 May 26; 4 pages (Box 27, Folder 219)
    - Invitations (Box 27, Folder 219)
      F.D. Roosevelt inauguration, 1945 Jan 20 [packet]
      L.B. Johnson inauguration, 1965 Jan 20 [packet]
    - Miscellaneous clippings, film prospectuses, etc., 11 pages (Box 27, Folder 220)
    - Awards (Box 28, Folder 221)
      Townsend Harris Medal Certificate (Alumni Association of City College, 1948)
      Academy Award of Merit for Outstanding Achievement Nomination for "Happiness is a Thing Called Joe" (1943)